

MARIA LAMARCHE

Luis F Thomen 68. Torre Gaia Apt 7B, Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

1-849-4040793 amore968@hotmail.com

Professional summary

A strategic global General Manager with a proven track record of success in the Hospitality Industry. Proven record of managing multi-cultural teams in different geographical zones and delivering quality and financially driven results successfully. Adaptable and motivated, developing opportunities that further established business goals.

Skills

- Leadership skills
- Financial acumen
- Commercial awareness

- Owners relationship
- Hotel Openings, Closures and Conversions
- Middle East region Expert

Experience

Complex General Manager

Jun 2019 - April 2021

Karisma Hotels and Resorts- Nickelodeon Resort Punta Cana & Sensatori Resort Punta Cana - Punta Cana, Dominican Republic

Overseeing the entire hotel operation for the Resort Complex. Achievement of all performance indicators in terms Guest Satisfaction, Financial and Quality. Managing relationship with partners Viacom and TUI. Handling closure of property during COVID19, remain on property during 7 months of closure leading the task force team and did a successful reopening on 5th November. The resort is 460 rooms, with 12 F&B outlets, a water park, and extensive leisure facilities with 950 team members.

www.karismahotels.com

General Manager

Jul 2015 - Jun 2019

Movenpick Hotels and Resorts - Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Started my career with Movenpick in Aqaba, Jordan overseeing the entire hotel operation of a 17 year old property. Achieved targets in terms of EBITDA, GOP, GSI and quality audits. Initiated several measures to control expenses and the up-grade of the property.

Transferred to Dubai for the successful opening of Movenpick Downtown in a period of six months and achievement of all performance indicators.

Established the property in the second raking of the comp set in terms of RGI.

Movenpick Aqaba is a 297 room property (including 87 apartments) Eight F&B outlets, private beach and conference facilities. Movenpick Downtown Dubai is 244 apartments with three F&B outlets and 250 staff.

www.movenpick.com

Cluster Hotel Manager - Millennium Kurdistan Hotel & Spa and Copthorne Baranan *Jul* 2014 - May 2015. Millennium Hotels & Resorts - Sulaimaniyah, Kurdistan, Iraq

Resident Manager Rotana Hotels - Rotana City Center Hotel - Doha, Qatar May 2013 - Jul 2014

Director of Operations Aug 2011 - May 2013

Hilton Hotels and Resorts - Double Tree by Hilton Beijing - Beijing, China

Director of Operations Jun 2010 - Jul 2011

Hilton Hotels and Resorts - Hilton Colombo - Colombo, Sri Lanka

Director of Operations Apr 2008 - Jun 2010

Hilton Hotels and Resorts - Athenee Palace Hilton Bucharest - Bucharest, Romania

Cluster Director of Business Development Jul 2006 - Apr 2008

Hilton Hotels and Resorts - Hilton Trinidad & Hilton Tobago - Port of Spain, Trinidad & Tobago

Jul 2003 - Jun 2006 Resident Manager

Dubai Marine Beach Resort and Spa - Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Director of Business Development Feb 2001 - Jan 2003

Le Meridien Hotels & Resorts - Le Meridien Abu Dhabi - Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

Director of Sales and Marketing Mar 2000 - Feb 2001

Intercontinental Hotels & Resorts - Crowne Plaza Kuwait - Kuwait City, State of Kuwait

Sales Manager Jan 1998 - Mar 2000

Intercontinental Hotels and Resorts - Crowne Plaza Abu Dhabi - Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

Business Development Manager Nov 1995 - Jan 1998

Grange Hotels - London, United Kingdom

Front Office Supervisor Sep 1993 - Sep 1995

The Hotel Russell - London, United Kingdom

Sales and Marketing Manager Feb 1988 - Nov 1992

Hotel Santo Domingo and Hotel Hispaniola. Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

Front Office Supervisor May 1986 - Nov 1987

Sheraton Santo Domingo Hotel & Casino - Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

Education

Master's degree: Business Administration, Hotel Administration

Universidad Catolica Santo Domingo - Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

Personal information

Nationality: Spanish & Dominican Republic

Marital Status: Single

Language

Spanish - Native speaker

English - Fluent

French - conversational

Italian - conversational